Guide to the Al Silverman Papers 1951-2003 MSS 136
© 2012 Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series I: Author Files
  - Subseries C: Recorded Interviews
    - Foster and Laurie - Police, D'Amodio, Liedy, Captain Rogers, D'Allessandro, TV funeral, coverage, Geraldo Rivera interview, Mrs. Laurie, Sound recording, audiocassette, Norelco, C-120., 1974 (Box 8, Media ID: 136.0045)
    - Foster and Laurie - Mel Ware, Dave, Alice Kuchlan, Sound recording, audiocassette, Norelco, C-120., 1974 (Box 8, Media ID: 136.0046)
    - Foster and Laurie - O'Neil, patrolman Frank Dudley, Sound recording, audiocassette, Norelco, C-120., 1974 (Box 8, Media ID: 136.0047)
    - Foster and Laurie - Al Romeo, Sgt. Gerry Hennessy, The Cool Ones, Sgt. Mason, Sound recording, audiocassette, Norelco, C-120., 1974 (Box 8, Media ID: 136.0048)
    - Foster and Laurie - patrol car, Larry Chiles, Sound recording, audiocassette, Norelco, C-120., 1974 (Box 8, Media ID: 136.0049)
    - Foster and Laurie - Sgt. Reedy and Wocial, Jim Liedy, Sound recording, audiocassette, Norelco, C-120., 1974 (Box 8, Media ID: 136.0050)
    - Foster and Laurie - Police, 9th Precinct, Peter S. Woods, detectives, Glover, Mahoney, Sound recording, audiocassette, Norelco, C-120., 1974 (Box 8, Media ID: 136.0051)
    - Foster and Laurie - Larry Perez, Antoinette, George Gibbons, patrol car, Sound recording, audiocassette, Norelco, C-120, 1974 (Box 8, Media ID: 136.0052)
    - Foster and Laurie - Mr. and Mrs. Laurie, Sound recording, audiocassette, Norelco, C-120., 1974 (Box 8, Media ID: 136.0053)
    - Foster and Laurie - Mrs. Laurie (Feb. 11, 1973), Steven Brenelsen, Sound recording, audiocassette, Norelco, C-120., 1974 (Box 8, Media ID: 136.0054)
    - Foster and Laurie - Anthony Laurie, Sound recording, audiocassette, Norelco, C-120., 1974 (Box 8, Media ID: 136.0055)
    - Foster and Laurie - Daryl Anderson, Jim Duffy, Sound recording, audiocassette, Norelco, C-120., 1974 (Box 8, Media ID: 136.0056)
    - Foster and Laurie - Lewis - Raftery, police team, Det. Al Romeo, Sound recording, audiocassette, Norelco, C-120., 1974 (Box 8, Media ID: 136.0057)
    - Foster and Laurie - Adelaide Laurie, Rich Peterson, Lewis - Raftery, Sound recording, audiocassette, Norelco, C-120., 1974 (Box 8, Media ID: 136.0058)
    - Foster and Laurie - Dale Duke, Iowa City, served with Foster, Vietnam, Michael Brown, Barbagello, Sound recording, audiocassette, Scotch, 3M., 1974 (Box 8, Media ID: 136.0059)
    - Foster and Laurie - 9th Div., Sound recording, audiocassette, BASF, C-120., 1974 (Box 8, Media ID: 136.0060)
    - Foster and Laurie - Brooks Matyi, Sound recording, audiocassette, Norelco, C-120., 1974 (Box 8, Media ID: 136.0061)
    - Foster and Laurie - Sayers, Doc Fox, Sound recording, audiocassette, RCA, 120 min., 1974 (Box 8, Media ID: 136.0062)
    - Foster and Laurie, Sound recording, audiocassette, Capehart, C-120., undated (Box 8, Media ID: 136.0063)
- Series II: Book of the Month Club
  The videocassettes in this series are available for use by researchers.
  - Subseries A: Paper Files
    This Subseries includes correspondence, annual reports, and memos from Silverman's tenure as CEO and chairman of Book of the Month Club.
    The Book of the Month Club meeting minutes are closed until 2023.
    - Book of the Month Club (correspondence, in-house memos), 1972 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Book of the Month Club (corresp., memos, annual report), 1973 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Book of the Month Club (corresp., memos, annual report), 1974 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Book of the Month Club (corresp., memos, memos, annual report), 1975 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Book of the Month Club (corresp., memos, annual report), 1976 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Book of the Month Club (corresp., memos, annual report), 1977 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Book of the Month Club (corresp., memos, clippings), 1978 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Book of the Month Club (corresp., memos, clippings), 1979 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Book of the Month Club (corresp., memos, clippings), 1980 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Book of the Month Club (corresp., memos, clippings), 1981 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Book of the Month Club (corresp., memos, clippings), 1982 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Book of the Month Club (corresp., memos, clippings), 1983 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Book of the Month Club (corresp., memos, clippings), 1984 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Book of the Month Club (corresp., memos, clippings), 1985 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Book of the Month Club (corresp., memos, clippings, 60th anniversary), 1986 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Book of the Month Club (corresp., memos, clippings, 60th anniversary), 1986 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Book of the Month Club (correspondence, etc.), 1987 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Book of the Month Club (Joe Savago file), 1987 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Book of the Month Club (corresp., clippings, 20th century project), 1988 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Book of the Month Club (corresp., clippings, Silverman's retirement), 1988 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Book of the Month Club (appointment of Brigette Weeks as BOMC editor), 1988 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Book of the Month Club (corresp., 20th century project), 1989-1990 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Book of the Month Club (course on contemporary novel taught at Yale), 1989-1990 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Book of the Month Club (speeches made over the BOMC years and beyond), 1984-1995 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Book of the Month Club (articles on book clubs), 1949-1984 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Book of the Month Club (articles on book clubs), 1986-2001 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - The Fragile Pleasure - Daedalus article on book clubs (corresp., research materials), 1983 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - The Fragile Pleasure, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - BOMC - "The Fragile Pleasure" (Daedalus article on book clubs from symposia on book publishing), 1983 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - BOMC - Strategic Plan, 1985-1990 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - BOMC: The Book (responses from publishers), 1986 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - BOMC: The Book (corresp., reviews, letters, corresp. with publisher Little, Brown), 1986 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - BOMC: The Book, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - BOMC: The Book, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - BOMC: The Book, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - BOMC: The Book, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - BOMC: The Book, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - BOMC: The Book, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - BOMC: The Book, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - BOMC: The Book, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - BOMC: The Book, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - BOMC: The Book, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - BOMC: The Book, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - BOMC: The Book, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - BOMC: The Book, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - BOMC: The Book, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - BOMC: The Book, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - BOMC: The Book, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - BOMC: The Book, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - BOMC: The Book, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - BOMC: The Book, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - BOMC: The Book, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - BOMC: The Book, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - BOMC: The Book, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - BOMC: The Book, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - BOMC: The Book (galleys), 1986 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - BOMC: The Book (galleys), 1986 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - BOMC: Judge files - RESTRICTED until 2023, 1972-1981 (Box 12)
    - BOMC: Judge files - RESTRICTED until 2023, 1981-1983 (Box 13)
    - BOMC: Judge files - RESTRICTED until 2023, 1984-1986 (Box 14)
    - BOMC: Judge files - RESTRICTED until 2023, 1986-1988 (Box 15)
  - Subseries B: Videotapes
    This subseries contains videocassettes from the Book of the Month Club.
    - BOMC: First Edition - Auchincloss, videorecording, VHS, Scotch., undated (Box 16, Media ID: 136.0064)
    - BOMC: First Edition - Bellow, Saul, videorecording, VHS, Fuji., undated (Box 16, Media ID: 136.0065)
    - BOMC: Caro, Robert, 28:30, videorecording, VHS, Scotch., undated (Box 16, Media ID: 136.0066)
    - Happy Birthday Mr. Fadiman!, videorecording, VHS, Scotch., undated (Box 16, Media ID: 136.0067)
    - BOMC: First Edition - Godwin 30:00, videorecording, VHS, Scotch., undated (Box 16, Media ID: 136.0068)
    - BOMC: First Edition - Gottlieb, Robert, 6/14/83, videorecording, VHS, Scotch., 1983 (Box 16, Media ID: 136.0069)
    - BOMC: First Edition - Hersh Protection, videorecording, VHS, Scotch., undated (Box 16, Media ID: 136.0070)
    - BOMC: First Edition - Howard, Maureen, 28:30, videorecording, VHS, Scotch., undated (Box 16, Media ID: 136.0071)
    - BOMC: First Edition - McGinnis, Joe, 6/17/83 videorecording, VHS, Scotch., 1983 (Box 16, Media ID: 136.0072)
    - Creative Television Association First Edition - Mailer, Norman, videorecording, VHS, Fuji., undated (Box 16, Media ID: 136.0073)
    - BOMC: First Edition - Morrison 30:00, videorecording, VHS, Scotch., undated (Box 16, Media ID: 136.0074)
    - BOMC: First Edition - Theroux, videorecording, VHS, Scotch., undated (Box 16, Media ID: 136.0075)
    - BOMC: Thomas, Lewis, 28:30, videorecording, VHS, Scotch., undated (Box 16, Media ID: 136.0076)
    - Creative Television Association First Edition - Tuchman, Barbara, videorecording, VHS, Fuji., undated (Box 16, Media ID: 136.0077)
    - BOMC: John Updike, Original videorecording, VHS, Scotch., undated (Box 16, Media ID: 136.0078)
    - BOMC: First Edition- Wetering, 30:00 videorecording, VHS, Scotch., undated (Box 16, Media ID: 136.0079)
- Series III: It's Not Over 'Til It's Over
  - Subseries A: Paper Files
    This subseries contains the research material used for, and drafts of "It's Not Over 'Til It's Over"
    - Sources and Acknowledgements, 2002 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - It's Not Over 'Til It's Over - Introduction, Undated (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Chapter 1 - "Merkele Forever" 1908, Undated (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Chapter 2 - "The Battle of the Century" 1923 (1 of 2), Undated (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Chapter 2 - "The Battle of the Century" 1923 (2 of 2), Undated (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Chapter 3 - "A Supreme Day for Tennis" 1937 (interviews and clippings), Undated (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Chapter 3 - "A Supreme Day for Tennis" 1937 (1 of 2), Undated (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Chapter 3 - "A Supreme Day for Tennis" 1937 (2 of 2), Undated (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Chapter 4 - "The Most Theatrical Home Run" 1951 (drafts), Undated (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Chapter 4 - "The Most Theatrical Home Run" 1951 (research), Undated (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Chapter 4 - "The Most Theatrical Home Run" 1951 (research and clippings 1 of 2), Undated (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Chapter 4 - "The Most Theatrical Home Run" 1951 (research and clippings 2 of 2), Undated (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Chapter 5 - "Sudden Death" 1958 (1 of 2), Undated (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Chapter 5 - "Sudden Death" 1958 (2 of 2), Undated (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Chapter 6 - "Head On, The Generations Collide" 1960 (1 of 2), Undated (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Chapter 6 - "Head On, The Generations Collide" 1960 (2 of 2), Undated (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Chapter 7 - "Chosen by the Gods" 1964 (1 of 2), Undated (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Chapter 7 - "Chosen by the Gods" 1964 (2 of 2), Undated (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Chapter 8 - "The Game of Games" 1968 (1 of 2), Undated (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Chapter 8 - "The Game of Games" 1968 (2 of 2), Undated (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Chapter 9 - "They Left it on the Table" 1971 (1 of 2), Undated (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Chapter 9 - "They Left it on the Table" 1971 (2 of 2), Undated (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Chapter 10 - "Body English" 1975, Undated (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Chapter 10 - "Body English" 1975 (clippings 1 of 2), Undated (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Chapter 10 - "Body English" 1975 (clippings 2 of 2), Undated (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Chapter 11 - "Do You Believe in Miracles" 1980 (1 of 2), Undated (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Chapter 11 - "Do You Believe in Miracles" 1980 (2 of 2), Undated (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Chapter 12 - "Weep No More My Lady" 1992 (1 of 2), Undated (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Chapter 12 - "Weep No More My Lady" 1992 (2 of 2), Undated (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Chapter 13 - "Awesome!" 1999 (1 of 2), Undated (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - Chapter 13 - "Awesome!" 1999 (2 of 2), Undated (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - PR, Reviews, Comments, Publicity, 2002 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Readings - Boston, Cambridge, New York, Kate - Len Lopate show, 2002 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Letters recieved, 2002-2003 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Contract, pre-pub letters, 1999-2002 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 2000-2002 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Revised draft - chapter 1, Undated (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Revised draft - chapter 2-4, Undated (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Revised draft - chapter 5-9, Undated (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Complete draft - Title page - chapter 7, 2002 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Complete draft - chapter 8-13, 2002 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Papers removed from media, Undated (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Subseries B: Books
    This subseries contains books which were used for research in the writing of "It's Not Over 'Til It's Over".
    - "Damn Senators" - Mark Gauvreau Judge, 2003 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - "A Day in the Life of Roger Angell" - Roger Angell, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - "Diz: The Story of Dizzy Dean and Baseball During the Great Depression" - Robert Gregory, 1992 (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - "The Natural" - Bernard Malamud, 1952 (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - "The New Baseball Reader" - Charles Einstein (ed.), 1991 (Box 20, Folder 17)
    - "Stranger to the Games" - Bob Gibson, 1994 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - "The Summer Game" - Roger Angell, 1990 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - "The Twentieth Century Treasury of Sports" - Al Silverman and Brian Silverman (eds.), 1992 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - "Willie's Time" - Charles Einstein, 1989 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Subseries C: Media
    This subseries contains audio recordings of interviews and other research material and video recordings of sports games and sports history programming.
    - Introduction - interviews with Billy Whelan, Charlie Ruddock (1 of 4), Undated; Format: microcassette (Box 22, Cassette ID: 136.0080)
    - Introduction - interviews with Billy Whelan, Charlie Ruddock (2 of 4), Undated; Format: microcassette (Box 22, Cassette ID: 136.0081)
    - Introduction - interviews with Billy Whelan, Charlie Ruddock (3 of 4), Undated; Format: microcassette (Box 22, Cassette ID: 136.0082)
    - Introduction - interviews with Billy Whelan, Charlie Ruddock (3 of 4), Undated; Format: microcassette (Box 22, Cassette ID: 136.0083)
    - Chapter 4 - Rachel Robinson interview, Undated; Format: microcassette (Box 22, Cassette ID: 136.0084)
    - Chapter 4 - Bobby Thomson interview, Undated; Format: microcassette (Box 22, Cassette ID: 136.0085)
    - Chapter 4 - Branca interview (1 of 2), Undated; Format: microcassette (Box 22, Cassette ID: 136.0086)
    - Chapter 4 - Branca interview (2 of 2), Undated; Format: microcassette (Box 22, Cassette ID: 136.0087)
    - Chapter 5 - Bob Daley interview, Undated; Format: microcassette (Box 22, Cassette ID: 136.0088)
    - Chapter 5 - John Steadman interview, Undated; Format: microcassette (Box 22, Cassette ID: 136.0089)
    - Chapter 7 - Billy Mills interview (1 of 2), Undated; Format: microcassette (Box 22, Cassette ID: 136.0090)
    - Chapter 7 - Billy Mills interview (2 of 2), Undated; Format: microcassette (Box 22, Cassette ID: 136.0091)
    - Chapter 8 - Champi interview, Undated; Format: microcassette (Box 22, Cassette ID: 136.0092)
    - Chapter 8 - Brian Dowling interview, Undated; Format: microcassette (Box 22, Cassette ID: 136.0093)
    - Chapter 10 - Sullivan interview (1 of 2), Undated; Format: microcassette (Box 22, Cassette ID: 136.0094)
    - Chapter 10 - Sullivan interview (2 of 2), Undated; Format: microcassette (Box 22, Cassette ID: 136.0095)
    - Chapter 11 - Hockey Guys (1 of 2), Undated; Format: microcassette (Box 22, Cassette ID: 136.0096)
    - Chapter 11 - Hockey Guys (2 of 2), Undated; Format: microcassette (Box 22, Cassette ID: 136.0097)
    - "Awesome Interviews" - [Aker], Undated; Format: microcassette (Box 22, Cassette ID: 136.0098)
    - "Awesome Interviews" - [DiLillo], Undated; Format: microcassette (Box 22, Cassette ID: 136.0099)
    - "Awesome Interviews" - [Foudy], Undated; Format: microcassette (Box 22, Cassette ID: 136.0100)
    - "Awesome Interviews" - [Millbaen], Undated; Format: microcassette (Box 22, Cassette ID: 136.0101)
    - "Awesome Interviews" - [Sharam], Undated; Format: microcassette (Box 22, Cassette ID: 136.0102)
    - George [Velsex] interview, Undated; Format: microcassette (Box 22, Cassette ID: 136.0103)
    - [I], Undated; Format: microcassette (Box 22, Cassette ID: 136.0104)
    - [3], Undated; Format: microcassette (Box 22, Cassette ID: 136.0105)
    - 1975 World Series, game 6: sides I and II, Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Cassette ID: 136.0106)
    - 1975 World Series, game 6: sides III and IV, Format: Audiocassette (Box 22, Cassette ID: 136.0107)
    - 42 Seconds, Undated; Format: Videocassette (Box 22, Cassette ID: 136.0108)
    - Al's Unitas Tape, Undated; Format: Videocassette (Box 22, Cassette ID: 136.0109)
    - Ali-Frazer 1: One Nation Divisible (revised), Undated; Format: Videocassette (Box 22, Cassette ID: 136.0110)
    - Arnold Palmer: Golf's Heart and Soul part 1, 1998; Format: Videocassette (Box 22, Cassette ID: 136.0111)
    - Arnold Palmer: Golf's Heart and Soul part 2, 1998; Format: Videocassette (Box 22, Cassette ID: 136.0112)
    - Billy Mills 10K Run, Tokyo Olympics, Undated; Format: Videocassette (Box 22, Cassette ID: 136.0113)
    - Dem Bums; Baseball, Undated; Format: Videocassette (Box 22, Cassette ID: 136.0114)
    - Do You Believe in Miracles: The Story of the 1980 U.S. Hockey Team, Undated; Format: Videocassette (Box 22, Cassette ID: 136.0115)
    - Duk-Ky, 1992; Format: Videocassette (Box 22, Cassette ID: 136.0116)
    - Duke, Kentucky - ESPN Classic Game of the Week, Undated; Format: Videocassette (Box 22, Cassette ID: 136.0117)
    - Duke vs. Kentucky, 3/28/92; Format: Videocassette (Box 22, Cassette ID: 136.0118)
    - Running Brave, 1983; Format: Videocassette (Box 22, Cassette ID: 136.0119)
    - Shot Heard Around the World, HBO, Undated; Format: Videocassette (Box 22, Cassette ID: 136.0120)
    - Sports of the Century - 1958 Colts / Giants, Undated; Format: Videocassette (Box 22, Cassette ID: 136.0121)
    - U.S - Russia, HBO, Undated; Format: Videocassette (Box 22, Cassette ID: 136.0122)
    - U.S. Open History, Undated; Format: Videocassette (Box 22, Cassette ID: 136.0123)
    - U.S. Women's Cup Soccer - Pasadena, 1999; Format: Videocassette (Box 22, Cassette ID: 136.0124)
    - World Series, game 6, 1975; Format: Videocassette (Box 22, Cassette ID: 136.0125)
  - Subseries D: Data Storage
    This series contains floppy disks and zip drives.
    Computer storage disks have not been preserved and are not available to researchers.
    - 51 floppy disks, Undated (Box 22)
    - 4 zip disks, Undated (Box 22)